<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bryan Adams Data Analysis</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bryan Adams Data Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning Step Data</title>
      <link>/post/cleaning-step-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cleaning-step-data/</guid>
      <description>My most recent paper that I published is titled, &amp;ldquo;Cardiometabolic thresholds for peak 30-min cadence and steps/day.&amp;rdquo; In the article we used multiple methods to establish thresholds for step activity. I was able to work with several outstanding and established faculty at West Point and other universities. The data was collected by NHANES using cluster sampling. This was my first time analyzing data of this nature, but fortunately there are several resources available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using RSelenium</title>
      <link>/post/using-rselenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-rselenium/</guid>
      <description>In class I like to use data that the Cadets can understand without me having to add context. One such data set is IOCT time and APFT scores. We have access to the data, but we have to log into our school account. To do this I have to use RSelenium. This allows me to manually log into my acount and navigate to the applicable pages. From their I am able to use rvest to scrape the remainder of the information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using RSelenium for Literature Reivew</title>
      <link>/post/using-rselenium-for-literature-reivew/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-rselenium-for-literature-reivew/</guid>
      <description>I was approached to see if there was a way to web scrape several articles from PubMed. I normally like to use rvest for web scraping, but it would not work because of the java script used to run PubMed. Luckily, RSelenium provides a way to easily interact with websites of this nature. This was my first use of RSelenium, but now I have a lot more efficient ways of using RSelenium and rvest together, although I am sure there are still better ways out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification Models (Logistic Regression)</title>
      <link>/post/classification-models-logistic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/classification-models-logistic-regression/</guid>
      <description>Logistic regression is the last method I shared with the Army unit. I believe logistic regression is an excellent classification model. You are limited to two outcomes, but it is interpretable.
Logistic RegressionThis example uses the titanic survival data to walk through a logistic regression example. The question is, what increases your probability of survival.
titanic = titanic::titanic_trainExploring the DataFigures 1, 2, and 3 graphically depict the relationship between possible explanatory variables and the response variable (surviving).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification Models (LDA)</title>
      <link>/post/classification-models-lda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/classification-models-lda/</guid>
      <description>Linear Discriminate Analysis (LDA) is a great classification method. It is simple and interpretable and can perform as well, if not better, than a lot of other fancier models (neural networks that are not interpretable).
Introduction to Linear Discriminant Analysis (LDA)I will be using the Iris Data set again. First I will split it into a “training” set and a “test” set. The test set will represent the unseen observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification Models (KNN)</title>
      <link>/post/classification-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/classification-models/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to share different classification models with a unit in the Army. I put these together to help give them what they could do as well as tell them some limitations of the models. I thought they might be useful for my students. This post is over KNN. I will have other post that discuss the other methods.
K-Nearest NeighborsK-Nearest Neighbors (KNN) classifier will classify an unseen instance by comparing it to a “training” set.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>