<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>modeling on Bryan Adams Data Analysis</title>
    <link>/categories/modeling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in modeling on Bryan Adams Data Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/modeling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CNN with keras</title>
      <link>/post/cnn-with-keras/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cnn-with-keras/</guid>
      <description>As part of an honors thesis I have cadets working on using RCNNs for image detection. The easiest place for them to begin is to learn CNNs. In keras there is the mnist data set. It is a data set of handwritten digits. It is a great data set to use to familiarize yourself with what images look like to a computer and how to build CNNs. This post attempts to provide a first time student information on how to use keras to build CNNs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification Models (Logistic Regression)</title>
      <link>/post/classification-models-logistic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/classification-models-logistic-regression/</guid>
      <description>Logistic regression is the last method I shared with the Army unit. I believe logistic regression is an excellent classification model. You are limited to two outcomes, but it is interpretable.
Logistic RegressionThis example uses the titanic survival data to walk through a logistic regression example. The question is, what increases your probability of survival.
titanic = titanic::titanic_trainExploring the DataFigures 1, 2, and 3 graphically depict the relationship between possible explanatory variables and the response variable (surviving).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification Models (LDA)</title>
      <link>/post/classification-models-lda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/classification-models-lda/</guid>
      <description>Linear Discriminate Analysis (LDA) is a great classification method. It is simple and interpretable and can perform as well, if not better, than a lot of other fancier models (neural networks that are not interpretable).
Introduction to Linear Discriminant Analysis (LDA)I will be using the Iris Data set again. First I will split it into a “training” set and a “test” set. The test set will represent the unseen observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification Models (KNN)</title>
      <link>/post/classification-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/classification-models/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to share different classification models with a unit in the Army. I put these together to help give them what they could do as well as tell them some limitations of the models. I thought they might be useful for my students. This post is over KNN. I will have other post that discuss the other methods.
K-Nearest NeighborsK-Nearest Neighbors (KNN) classifier will classify an unseen instance by comparing it to a “training” set.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>